

JAMES WILSON

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Cutting-edge full stack developer with 6 years of experience in software engineering, web development and blockchain development.

Experienced with architecting, developing and deploying web applications, smart contracts and decentralized applications.

Advanced knowledge of multiple programming languages, frameworks and extensive familiarity with blockchain infrastructure and DBMS.

CONTACT

james0376991@gmail.com 65 Walnut Street South Hamilton, ON

SOFT SKILLS

Flexibility
Communication
Collaboration
Creativity
Efficiency
Accountability
Self-Innovation
Self-Starter
Critical-Thinking
Problem-Solving

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2011 - Nov 2015

University of Toronto, Computer Science Toronto, ON, Canada

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK/WEB3 ENGINEER

Pastal Network, REMOTE / Jan 2022 - Now

- Architected and designed the NFT bridge between Ethereum, Solana and Pastel network referencing Wormhole and Cosmos IBC protocol.
- Built NFT picks application with React, Node.js and integrated payment service with Stripe

FULL STACK/WEB3 ENGINEER

Bitdeal, REMOTE / May 2020 - Dec 2021

- Integrated smart contracts to frontend applications using React, Web3.js and Ethers.js.
- Architected, designed and developed smart contracts using Cosmwasm and Rust.
- Built frontend applications for Defi app using React and Redux.
- Developed smart contracts with Solidity for bonding & staking in Defi application.
- Worked on sports project with Flow/Cadence and React to build a fast, decentralized and developer-friendly blockchain application.

COSMOS BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

Kira Network, Inc, REMOTE / Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

- Analyzed and researched Cosmos Network and application-specific blockchain development using Golang, Cosmos SDK and Tendermint.
- Architected, designed and developed minimum viable product for application-specific blockchain using Golang, Starport and Cosmos.
- Integrated Inter-Blockchain Communication Protocol to SDK-based application with Golang.
- Worked on the frontend application using Vue3 and Quasar framework.
- Implemented multi-chain smart contract with CosmWasm and Rust.
- Researched and studied **Ethermint**, a scalable, highthroughout Proof-of-Stake blockchain, compatible with **Ethereum**.



JAMES WILSON

SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

LANGUAGES

C/C++ 10 years
JavaScript 8 years
TypeScript 6 years
Python 5 years
Golang 3 years
Solidity 4 years
Rust 2 years

FRAMEWORKS

React/Redux 6 years Vue/Vuex 6 years Node.js/Express 6 years Diango 5 years Hardhat/Truffle 4 years Cosmos/Starport 3 years Solana/Anchor 2 years **Terra** 1 year

EXTRA

CosmWasm Ethermint GraphQL Next.js Quasar Laravel Flask

Ruby on Rails

WORK EXPERIENCE

BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

Yes Man Enterprises, Inc., Miami, FL / Feb 2018 - Jun 2020

- Worked on the development and implementations of Defi application with **React**, **Solidity** and **Truffle**.
- Architected, developed and deployed ERC20 Cryptocurrency, Smart contracts and web application using Solidity, Hardhat and React.
- Implemented, tested and audited open-source software to interact with on-chain smart contracts.
- Wrote technical documentation to communicate key points to stakeholders.
- Researched and investigated Cosmos SDK and Cosmos Network.

FULL STACK(FE HEAVY) DEVELOPER

Absolute Web, Miami, FL / Jan 2016 - Apr 2018

- Improved the page speed by 17% for the ecommerce site that generates \$21M annually in revenue by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance with React, GraphQL and Apollo.
- Designed, developed and deployed full-stack web applications according to business objectives and needs of various clients with React, Vue, Django, Express.js.
- Implemented SEO in Vue application for e-commerce site with a catalog of 20000+ products leading to an increase in page views per session of 23% with SSR in Nuxt.js and Quasar framework.
- Worked on building customer-facing web application with Express.js, Prisma, Vue.js, PostgreSQL and Node.js.
- Built Progressive Web Application (PWA) with React,
 TypeScript and GraphQL (Relay).

CERTIFICATIONS

CERTIFIED BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

Blockchain Council, Sep 2020

CERTIFIED WEB PROFESSIONAL

CIW, Jun 2018